这是二零二二年河北省初中毕业生
升学文化课考试英语。
语试卷听力部分，听力部分共有五道题，第一题至第四题为选择题，
第五题为填空题。
做题时，先将答案答在试卷上，在听力测试结束后，再将答案。
沿途到答题卡上。
现在是听力试音时间。
Excuse me, but could you tell me how to get to the cinema?
Which cinema? The Capitol Cinema.
Oh, it's a long way from here.
You'd better take a bus.
Which bus shall I take then?
I think you need to take number seven.
Thanks a You are welcome.
试音到此结束。
now. B, and Number one, I think you do a good job.
第一题，听句子，选出句子中所包含的信息。
下面你将听到五个。
句子，每个句子读两遍，请你听完句子的第二遍朗读后，从各小题所给出
三个选项中，选出包含所听信息的选项。
I think you do a good job.
Number two, would you like to drink some tea?
you like to drink some tea?
Number three, teacher's day is on September the 10th.
Teacher's is on September the 10th.
Number four, now let's read the text aloud.
Now let's read the text aloud.
Number five, Peter is going to meet his uncle at the airport.
Peter is going to meet his uncle at the airport.
第二题，听句子，选出该句的最佳答语。
下面你将听到五个句。
句子。
每个句子读两遍，请你听完句子的第二遍朗读后，从各小题所给出的
三个选项中选出该句的最佳答语。
Peter is going to at at at the airport.
Number six, have a nice weekend,
Jane. Have a nice weekend, Jane.
Number seven, hello, is that Mr.
Green speaking? Hello, is that Mr.
Green speaking? Number eight, I'm sorry to keep you waiting so long.
I'm sorry to keep you waiting so long.
Number nine, Jack, do you often do housework?
Jack, do you often do housework?
Number ten, if you hope someone is successful, what would you say?
If you hope someone is successful, what would you say?
If you is successful, what say?
三题：听对话和问题，选择正确答案。
下面你将听到四组对话和八个问题，
每组对话和问题读两遍。
请你听完对话和问题的第二遍朗读后，从各小题。
所给出的
三个选项中选出正确答案。
Listen choose me, Lily.
请听第一组对话，回答第十一题。
Yes? Could you help me with my math?
A minute, please.
I'm finishing the picture.
Excuse me, Lily.
Yes? Could you help me with my math?
A minute, please.
I'm finishing the picture.
number eleven, what is Lily doing?
What is Lily doing?
请听第二组对话，回答第十二题。
Cindy, shall we go to the zoo this Sunday?
Sorry, but I want to visit my grandpa's farm.
Sounds good. Can I go with you?
I'd to feed the Great.
My grandpa will be happy to see you.
Cindy, shall we go to the zoo this Sunday?
Sorry, but I want to visit my grandpa's farm.
Sounds good. Can I go with you?
I'd to feed the Great.
My grandpa will be happy to see you.
number twelve, where will they go?
Where will they go?
请听第三组对话，回答第十三至十五题。
Hello, what can I do for you?
Hello, I'm a new student.
I'd like to borrow some books.
Well, you need to write down your name here on the card.
Okay, here you are.
Thanks. And we have books on arts, medicine, history, and many other subjects.
I'd like some about history.
Uh They are just on your left.
Thank you. How many can I borrow at a time?
Three. Good. I'll take the three books.
How long can I keep them?
Two weeks. And please return them in time.
Sure I will.
Thanks a lot.
Hello, what can I do for you?
Hello, I'm a new student.
I'd like to borrow some books.
Well, you need to write down your name here on the card.
Okay, here you are.
Thanks. And we have books on arts, medicine, history, and many other subjects.
I'd like some about history.
Uh They are just on your left.
Thank you. How many can I borrow at a time?
Three. Good. I'll take the three books.
How long can I keep them?
Two weeks. And please return them in time.
Sure I will.
Thanks a Question number 13.
should the girl write on the card?
What should the girl write on the card?
Question number 14.
What books does she want to borrow?
What books Question number 15.
How many books does she borrow this time?
请听第四组对话，回答第十六至十八题。
Come and have a look,
Here are some photos of my holiday in Hainan.
Did you go with your family,
Yes. This is my mother.
She's walking on the beach.
Oh, the sea looks so blue.
And this is my sister Betty.
She's swimming. This is you, Tom.
You're buying bananas.
Yes. The fruit is really cheap there.
And here's your family.
You're having a picnic on the grass.
Yeah. We're enjoying ourselves.
Come and have a look, Susan.
Here are some photos of my holiday in Hainan.
Did you go with your family,
Yes. This is my mother.
She's walking on the beach.
Oh, the sea looks so blue.
And this is my sister Betty.
She's swimming. This is you, Tom.
You're buying bananas.
Yes. The fruit is really cheap there.
And here's your family.
You're having a picnic on the grass.
Yeah. We're enjoying ourselves.
Question number 16.
Where is Tom's mother walking?
Question number 17.
Who is buying bananas?
Question number 18.
What are the family doing?
第四题：听短文和问题，选择正确答案。
下面你将听到两篇短文和七个问题，
每篇短文和问题读两遍。
请你听完短文和问题的第二遍朗读后。
根据所听内容，从各小题所给出的
三个选项中选出正确答案。
请听第一篇短文，回答第十九、二十题。
Anne. This is Henry.
How are you?
The soccer team needs a new player.
I think you should join the team.
You can run fast and do it well.
You will be great.
Mr. coach, is going to see players at 10 o tomorrow.
You need to wear sports clothes.
Let's meet at 9.30 at the school gate.
Is that okay?
Hello, Anne. This is Henry.
How are you?
The soccer team needs a new player.
I think you should join the team.
You can run fast and do it well.
You will be great.
Mr. Lee, the coach, is going to see players at 10 o tomorrow.
You need to wear sports clothes.
Let's meet at 9.30 at the school gate.
Is that okay?
number 19. What does Henry ask Anne to do?
What does Henry ask Anne to do?
Question number 20.
What time will they meet tomorrow?
请听第二。
篇短文回答第二十一至二十五题。
Using who, what, where,
when, why, or how.
If someone asks you a yes or no question, try to give a longer answer.
For example, a friend might ask, Hey, have you seen the new movie?
You could just answer no or never.
But it's better for you to say more, like,
No, but I plan to see it soon.
How about you?
Do not worry about your pronunciation.
If your pronunciation is a little different,
try speaking slowly, and then the other person will still understand you.
you are traveling in an English -speaking country,
be brave and speak in English.
You may make a new friend.
That's my idea about how to keep a conversation going in English.
How to keep a going in English?
Well, that's a good question.
First, listen to the other person carefully, so that you can ask a follow -up
question. For example,
when someone says,
just got back from a trip to Canada.
You can ask him a question using who,
what, where, when, why, or how.
If someone asks you a yes or no question, try to give a longer answer.
For example, a friend might ask, Hey, have you seen the new movie?
You could just answer no or never.
But it's better for you to say more, like, No, but I plan to see it soon.
How about you?
Do not worry about your pronunciation.
If your pronunciation is a little different,
try speaking slowly, and then the other person will still understand you.
When you are traveling in an English -speaking country, be brave and speak in
English. You may make a new friend.
That's my idea about how to keep a conversation going in English.
Question No. Why should you listen to the other person carefully?
Question No. Which is the best answer to a no question?
Which is the best answer to a no question?
Question No. How should you speak if your pronunciation is a little different?
Question No. What should you do when you travel in English -speaking countries?
Question No. What is the speaker talking about?
Question 26 I really love sports, and I play football often.
第五题，听短文填空，下面。
你将听到一篇短文，短文读两遍。
请你听完短文的第二遍朗读后，根据短文的内容和提示，在信息表中相应
的横线上填入所缺信息。
It's very interesting.
Oh, you know, I'm here to learn Chinese.
I hope I can get help from you.
If you have any difficulty in English learning, please come to me.
I believe we'll be good friends soon.
Hi, my name is Linda.
I'm 15 years old, and I'm from England.
See, my hair is different from yours.
It's long and red.
I get good marks at school.
My teachers say I'm quite smart.
I really love sports, and I play football often.
It's very interesting.
Oh, you know, I'm here to learn Chinese.
I hope I can get help from you.
If you have any difficulty in English learning, please come to me.
I believe we'll be good friends soon.
听力部分到此结束。
预祝同学们取得好成绩。